hey everybody my name is Taylor Glenn
and this is my channel Taylor tries
where I try new things and I try to
teach you new things and today I'm gonna
try to teach you how to juggle three
bolts yeah all right so before you can
learn how to juggle
you have to understand what juggling is
most people think this is juggling
throwing three balls up in the air and
continuously catching and growing them
again yeah maybe that's the official
definition but when somebody says that
they're juggling what they really mean
is that they're gonna throw stuff up in
the air drop it pick it up and do it
again
that's what juggling is all about it's
about messing up and getting better in
little increments every time you throw
the ball and it's important to know that
going in because otherwise you're gonna
get super frustrated and think oh I
can't do this I'm really bad I'm
uncoordinated dropping is a part of it
it's a big part of it it's okay enjoy
the journey of juggling enjoy the drops
so in order to juggle you have to have
something to juggle juggling balls
that's what these are called juggling
balls specifically these are juggling
beanbags there's different types of
juggling balls but when you start out I
think beanbags are the best way to go I
highly recommend a really good beginner
set that's not very expensive and super
durable there's a link to that in the
description I really recommend it if for
some reason you can't get your hands on
that beginner set that I recommend you
can use any other sort of round heavy
enough object to learn how to juggle
now some people try to use tennis balls
I don't recommend that tennis balls are
too light and they'll bounce everywhere
when you drop just avoid them if you're
really in a pinch there are tutorials
online on how to make your own juggling
balls with balloons or you can go to
your local sporting goods store and see
if they have any hacky sacks hacky sacks
are not great they're too light and
they're too flimsy but they will do the
trick if you really can't get your hands
on the good set that I mentioned earlier
but like really you should get that
other set it's a really good deal okay
so the pattern we're gonna learn today
is called the three ball cascade it
looks like this
in the 3-ball cascade all you're doing
is throwing a ball from your right hand
to your left hand and as that ball comes
down you're throwing the next ball from
your left hand to your right hand and
then you repeat it's just right left
right left forever all right let's break
that down take your three juggling balls
drop two of them
we got one juggling ball it sounds
really silly but you want to just get
comfortable with the idea of throwing
and catching if you haven't done that in
a while
your brain might need a refresher so get
comfortable it doesn't matter how it
looks just feel what the ball feels like
how to catch awesome now let's get into
the actual throws that we're gonna want
to do for our 3-ball cascade in order to
be the most efficient we're gonna want
to aim our throws we don't want them
just going all over the place we want to
aim for two specific points these two
points are basically going to be
shoulder width apart and create kind of
a rectangle a little bit above our head
these are our points yeah when you throw
it with your right hand you're gonna aim
for that left point when you throw with
your left hand you're gonna aim for the
right point
when you catch you're gonna catch the
ball slightly outside of your shoulder
and then scoop it in a little bit for
the throw do that like a lot get
comfortable throwing the ball over and
over again okay so I know some of you
are gonna start cheating you're gonna
start doing this because you want to be
able to juggle super low and exciting
just bear with me focus on that higher
throw because when you start doing three
it's going to be more beneficial in the
long run once you feel comfortable with
that
you can move on to two and things get
exciting to do two balls we're gonna
apply that same technique we're gonna
try to hit those two points that I
talked about but now this time when that
first ball is coming down you're gonna
throw the second ball so you're gonna
hit the first point and then the second
point typically you're gonna want to
start with the hand that is your
dominant hand right left right left or
if you're left handed left right left
right that being said some people I've
noticed have a really hard time throwing
that second ball they just can't get it
out because of muscle memory if that is
a problem that you're having try
starting with the other hand left right
left right sometimes I can force you out
of that habit of holding on to the
second ball so really practice that over
and over again focus on getting the ball
it's the same height they should be
hitting those two points okay so you're
working on that you might be
encountering a few hiccups one of the
most common problems I see is that
you're throwing the first ball and the
second ball goes forward away from you
if that's happening to you really try to
focus on that second throw aim for that
spot throw it with intention up up if
that's still not working and you just
can't seem to get it try starting with
your non-dominant hand sometimes that
can force the muscle memory to be better
the other thing you might be doing is
throwing the balls too quickly like this
you really don't want to throw that
second ball until the first one is
coming down
pay attention to the rhythm if you're
going up up catch catch it's too fast it
should be up up up up
[Music]
okay so practice that two ball exercise
over and over again try mixing it up
where you go right left catch catch
left right catch catch right left catch
catch
left right catch catch and once you feel
comfortable with that pick up that third
ball okay so now we have a lot going on
I'm actually gonna switch out my
beanbags for a set of balls that are
different colors so that you can see
more easily what I'm doing tada this is
gonna be easier to follow so to start
you're gonna have one ball in one hand
and two balls in the other hand I
typically recommend starting with two
balls in your dominant hand you're gonna
hold one kind of in your palm and the
other one more up near the fingers so
we're gonna start with this ball and
it's just gonna be like we did with one
in two balls before we were just doing
right left catch catch
but now when that second throw comes
down we're gonna just throw our right
hand again right left right or if you're
left handed left right left
just try doing those three throws right
left right catch remember to aim for
those two points just like we were with
one and two balls right left right the
ball shouldn't be coming forward or
backwards so none of this and none of
this you want everything to stay
relatively in the same plane right left
right right left right catch that's
called the three-ball flash that's a
really big step if you can do that take
a second and appreciate yourself you
can't do it yet remember that you will
keep trying once you have those three
throws you can go on to a fourth one one
two three four catch right left right
left catch four left right left right
catch I'm a big fan of this learning
method if you feel comfortable with four
throws add a fifth row once you feel
comfortable with the fifth row add a
sixth row eventually you won't be
counting throws anymore 1 2 3 4 5 stop 1
2 3 4 5 6
stop and then from there it's literally
just repeating right left right left
right left right lower though forever
right left right left right left right
left right left and eventually you can
bring it down but it's the same pattern
right
right left right left right left but
this comes with time focus on doing the
nice slow hire pattern first okay so I
know a lot of you are gonna start
ignoring those two points and you're
gonna just start throwing balls as much
as you can that's fine I'm not your mom
you can do whatever you want but if you
do it the way that I'm teaching you and
really focus on high enough throws that
you have time to get accuracy down it's
gonna pay off in the long run so really
just like try to do it this way for a
little bit and then you can go off and
go rogue like I have a crazy person now
officially with the 3-ball cascade once
you get six catches you have done what
we call a qualify you have qualified the
pattern so that's a good goal to have
six catches and then from there just add
more and more and more and become an
awesome person who juggles like me okay
now I want to talk about some of the
things that people have trouble with
some of the things that might be
frustrating you so one of the biggest
things that I see people struggle with
is being able to throw the ball getting
the ball out of your hand there's like
this muscle memory thing that is
preventing you from physically throwing
a ball right after you throw the other
one if this is your problem this is what
I want you to do try throwing the three
ball is up but don't catch them remember
to keep the timing and the height right
but don't catch them right left right
do that over and over again until the
idea of throwing a ball after you've
thrown another one doesn't feel so
foreign and then you can work on
catching if you only need to catch the
first ball just do that right left right
then you can move on to catching the
first two balls right left right
eventually you should be able to get all
three catches right left right I also
think it's really important that every
time you get one in those catches you
should pat yourself on the back like
it's hard it's a hard skill to learn but
you did it even if you just got one
catch you did it be kind to yourself in
this process you're going to drop don't
get discouraged some of you might be
experiencing the situation now where you
can throw and you can catch but your
pattern looks all over the place and
you're having to move around a lot to
catch it this is super common first of
all that will fix over time the more you
practice that will get better you'll
just get natural e better at throwing
and catching but there are some things
that can help you in those scenarios so
I'm gonna go over them right now the
first thing you might be doing is where
you're lifting your arms up really high
to catch the balls gravity works guys
you can bring your hands down I'm not
catching them up here but super
inefficient the ball will come down so
let the ball come down and as it does
drop your hand even more and get ready
to throw the throw again really just try
to keep your hands more down by your
hips and less up by your chest the other
problem you might be encountering is you
might be chasing the balls away from you
this is a really common problem and
really it just comes down to the fact
that you might be pushing the ball a
little too far forward and not enough up
slow down your pattern really focus on
hitting those two points and breaking it
down and just remember that with time
those throws will get more accurate the
other thing you can do is practice up
against the wall some people find that
that's helpful in preventing them from
going forward the other problem you
might be having is the opposite you
might be pulling the balls towards you
again a very common problem very similar
to the last one you're just scooping the
ball is too far back when you should be
doing it straight up you want to break
it down again and aim for those two
spots really take your time with each
throw and just know that eventually it
will fix itself
well lastly I have a couple bonus tips
the first being that maybe you're
getting sick of dropping maybe you have
a bad back or you just aren't feeling
good picking up so much a really great
way to get around that is to juggle over
your bed as long as your bed isn't
higher than your hips then that can be
really helpful because when you drop
it's just going to drop right on your
bed and you can pick it up again so
definitely utilize that if you want the
next bonus tip is about practice
schedule some people when they're trying
something new they do better if they
just obsessively practice for a couple
hours and until they get it I'm not
really one of those people sometimes I
have to break it up into smaller chunks
for me I find it really beneficial just
to work on something for 10-15 minutes
every single day and I guarantee you if
you practice this technique for 10
minutes everyday you'll be surprised at
how quickly you can do 3 balls your last
tip is no matter how great tutorials are
and how great my tutorials are I'm so
humble it's great sometimes you really
can't be like an actual teacher luckily
there are juggling clubs all around the
world look in your local area
look on Facebook look online see if
there's any groups near you and I
guarantee you if there is a group near
you any juggler there will teach you and
help you on your pattern so please reach
out to your local community all right
that is my tutorial hopefully you found
that helpful juggling is such a fun
awesome hobby it's good for you in so
many ways and the fun thing about it is
just because you've learned the 3-ball
cascade it doesn't mean that you've
reached the end of juggling there's so
much more there's more three ball tricks
you can learn four and five and six and
seven balls you can keep going you can
learn clubs there's knives and torches
there's so many fun things to do and if
you get the three ball cascade and you
feel like you want to learn some more
you can check out my channel there are
more tutorials on there and I'm making
more all the time
so consider subscribing and turning on
notifications and all that stuff so that
you can see when I make more and support
me and stuff if you want to go the extra
mile you can support me on patreon and
join my Auto Club and get all sorts of
insider goodies and stuff and if you
want some juggling inspiration you can
go follow me on my Instagram at Taylor
underscore tries where I post a lot of
juggling stuff and some other fun stuff
too so yeah go follow that
you want all right that's it bye banana
then squirrels stop it